

# NAYOMI RASHMIKA

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Galgodagama, Dambagalla, Monaragala

**\** 0713763838

nayomirashmikaaa@gmail.com

https://github.com/nayomi16

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/nayomi-rashmika

An ambitious individual with a high capacity to concurrently manage studies and extracurricular activities. Having experience in software and over three years of experience in Java and web application development is currently seeking an opportunity to contribute to a challenging work environment to deliver high-quality software solutions.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Software Engineer Trainee Virtusa (Pvt) Ltd

Aug 2020 - Mar 2020

- Performed duties as a trainee software engineer in the Afin Consortium team.
- Worked on the Apix platform project of the ASEAN Financial Innovation Network (AFIN) under the Angular framework & developed 3 components with many Angular service functions to take dynamic data and other from the backend.
- Developed unit testing functions for 4 microservices using Junit, Mockito, and Codepro,
- Unit coverage was increased by up to 80%.

#### **EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATIONS**

#### **B.Sc. Degree in Information Technology**

Nov 2016 - Present

Faculty of Information Technology, University of Moratuwa (Current GPA - 3.341)

## **Comprehensive Master JAVA Developer certificate course**

May 2019 - Dec 2019

Offered by Institute of Java & Software Engineering, Panadura, Sri Lanka. Covered all the programming fundamentals, 00P, Design Patterns, DBMS, Application Architectures, and more.

#### Advanced Business Solution Developer certificate course

Dec 2019 - Jun 2020

Offered by Institute of Java & Software Engineering, Panadura, Sri Lanka. Covered all the web application technologies using Java Enterprise Edition and Enterprise Edition Frameworks (Spring with Angular).

## **Machine Learning Foundations**

Feb 2020 - May 2020

Offered by Sri Lanka Academy of Innovative Education

Online Java Course Oct 2020

Offered by Udemy (Credentials)

#### **AWS Fundamentals: Going Cloud Native**

Oct 2020

Authorized by Amazon Web Services and offered through Coursera

#### Online Java Design Patterns and Architecture course

April 2020

Offered by Udemy (Credentials)

#### Online HTML & CSS course in Udemy

Oct 2020

Offered by Udemy (Credentials

## PROJECT EXPERIENCE

## National COVID Management System (Back-end & Front-end)

Individual Project | Aug 2020 - Ongoing

Developing a web application to be used to efficiently manage patients having COVID19 symptoms with bed reservation and queue controlling mechanism and to provide country, district, and hospital level patient statistics.

Technologies: Spring Boot, Angular, Spring Data JPA with MySQL server, Git, Maven, JWT

Contribution: An individual project that was planned and executed from start to end.

#### **Project Finance Management System**

Second year Industrial Project | 5 Members | Feb 2018 - Aug 2018

The main purpose of this project is to manage all activities related to the projects within a software company.

Technologies: Node.is backend, React.is frontend, and the Database was built using MYSQL, Git

Contribution: Implemented a module for handling the project's finances that can manage the transactions & projects that enter the system.

#### **Car Protecting System**

First year Hadware Project | 5 Members | Feb 2017-Aug 2017

Introduced a safety system, car crashing can be eliminated using this system.

Technologies: C programming, ATmega32A

Contribution: I have learned about details regarding Atmega32 microcontroller and learned how to measure a distance using an ultrasonic distance sensor(HC-SR04T). I created a decoder circuit to give triggered signals from the Atmega32 chip to ultrasonic distance sensors.

#### **Detecting Phishing Web Sites Using Machine Learning**

Final Year Research Project | 3 Members | Ongoing

The goal of this project is to develop a system to detect phishing websites using machine learning algorithms. This would create awareness for users to identify phishing websites and legitimate websites separately. Our system aimed at enabling the user to access the websites securely by distinguishing phishing websites from legitimate ones. Networks in automated production lines to demonstrate an Artificial Intelligence-driven pilot factory.

Technologies: Python for Machine Learning algorithm & Django

#### **COMPETITIONS**

#### Hack-Moral v1.0 2018 organized by the Faculty of IT, University of Moratuwa

Coding Competition | Placed among the top 10

# MoraXtreame 3.0 2018 organized by the IEEE University of Moratuwa Branch

Interfaculty 12hrs Coding Competition | 14th place over 120+ teams

#### FIT code rush 2018 organized by the INTECS of Faculty of IT

12hrs Coding Competition

#### IEEEXtreame 14.0 2020 organized by the IEEE University of Moratuwa Branch

Programming Competition | 744th place over 3700+ teams

#### **EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES**

#### Company coordinator in "Are You Ready 2018 - The Official Career Fair of University of Moratuwa"

Represented Mobitel on behalf of the university and managed all needs of company interviewers and helped in matching and shortlisting suitable candidates for interviews.

# Company coordinator in "FIT FUTURE CAREERS – The Official Career Fair of University of Moratuwa"

Represented Pravous Labs on behalf of the IT faculty and managed all needs of company interviewers and helped in matching and shortlisting suitable candidates for interviews.

#### Member of the IEEE Student Branch, University of Moratuwa

Medium Writer: https://medium.com/@nayomirashmika

So far, several blogs related to software engineering have been written.

### **REFERENCES**

Dr. (Mr.) L. Ranathunga

Senior Lecturer Faculty of IT

University of Moratuwa Email: lochandaka@uom.lk Telephone: 0712207030 Dr. S. Ahangama

Senior Lecturer Faculty of IT University of Moratuwa

Email: supunmali@uom.lk

Telephone: 0714866652